Randy Razafindrabe

Software Developer / Web Developer

Montréal, QC (Authorized to work in Canada)

 Phone: +1 (438) 540-5401
 Linkedin
 E-mail: raza.randy@gmail.com

Summary

Graduated in **Computer Science and Software Development** with fundamental knowledge in **software design**, development and **testing**, I have excellent **analytical and technical** programming skills to thrive as a developer.

My goal is to join a team where we collaborate effectively to successfully complete development projects and optimize available resources. As an individual, my ability to meet deadlines, my ability to communicate effectively and manage projects are important assets.

I am determined to play a key role in the overall success of the team and the company

Skills

- Backend: Python (Flask), Java, NodeJS, RISC-V. Frontend: Javascript, CSS3, HTML5, ReactJS, Bootstrap.
- Skills developed: AGILE, Scrum, Data Structures, Object Oriented Programming, Database Management Systems, Assembly Language, Web Development, Software Quality Testing, Full Stack Programming, MacOs, Linux (Ubuntu).XML/ HTML, Sql Developer, Spring, Valgrind, Compiler Explorer, JUnit, CUnit, Docker.
- Great adaptability and organizational capacity, stress management, adaptability, sense of priorities.
- Knowledge of customer needs, good empathy and good commercial vision.
- International professional experience in Canada, France, Spain and the United Kingdom.
- Ability to work comfortably in English and French speaking environments.

Application Development Projects

aPhyloGeo plus plus | Montreal, QC

Jan 2023 - May 2023

Description: Design and implementation of a **new multiplatform application** for the **analysis of phylogenetic trees (MacOs and Linux)**. Project carried out under the direction of Professor Nadia Tahiri from the University of Sherbrooke with 3 other students

Languages and libraries Used: Python, QtDesigner, PyQt5, Matpotlib.

- Worked throughout the development lifecycle to build and maintain code, eliminating 20 unique bugs.
- Using coding best practices and object-oriented programming techniques such as abstraction and association to work on full-stack software development projects.
- Adding functions: map alignment of genetic sequences generation of the climatic and genetic tree -Visualization of statistics.
- Improving GUI with PyQt5 and QtDesigner.

Canvascii | Montreal, QC

Jan 2023 - May 2023

Description: Creation of a program where the user can draw on a canvas on the terminal. **Languages and librairies Used**: C.

- Worked across creation of a canvas.
- Implementation of the different brushes, colours and geometric shapes.
- Use of the Bresenham algorithm for plotting an arc by midpoint.

Description: Design of a game as part of a university project.

Languages and libraries Used: C, Sprite, SDL2 and SDL2_gfxPrimitives graphic part, SDL_mixer for the audio part.

- Developping the game base on the existing game Super Hexagon, made in C with GCC for compilation.
- Integration with gitlabCI/CD.

Professional Experience

Sales Representative | Webinterpret, Spain

Jul 2018 - Sept 2021

E-commerce solution specializing in translation and localization of online stores to help sellers expand their international presence..

- Evaluate user account performance, provide solutions and improvements to increase revenue and satisfaction.
- Convert customers from free trial to paid plans through performance data (GMV, promotional offers).

Customer Care Representative | RATESDOTCA, Toronto, ON

Aug 2017 – Apr 2018

Online service that provides information and quotes to compare rates for insurance, mortgages, and other financial products.

- Provide clients with the best quote insurance hey can get and connect them with the insurance provider or intermediaries.
- Work in collaboration with different insurance companies to meet customer needs.

Team Leader | Nike, France

May 2016 - Jul 2017

Sale of multisport clothing, shoes and equipment.

- Train and motivate the team to achieve the targets. Organize meetings (monitoring turnover and performance indicators. Act as a voice of encouragement (individual and collective challenges).
- Set daily, weekly and monthly sales goals. Motivate the team to achieve goals. Encourage and reward the team and set up "employee of the month" bonuses or awards.
- Participate in the interview process. Provide team members with guidance and training to achieve goals. Orient and train new staff and focus on improving the teams sales performance.

Education

University of Québec in Montréal Certificate in Computer Science and Software Developping Montreal, QC Jan 2022 – Aug 2023

Institut KFP Cogefi
Two-Year Technical Degree in Management
(Technical DEC equivalent)

Sept 2008 – June 2010

Paris, France